<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on Ukant Jadia</title>
    <link>https://ukantjadia.me/categories/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on Ukant Jadia</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 11:48:21 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ukantjadia.me/categories/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>U2F Zero in Firefox</title>
      <link>https://ukantjadia.me/post/u2f-zero-in-firefox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2018 11:48:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukantjadia.me/post/u2f-zero-in-firefox/</guid>
      <description>I recently got a U2F Zero, a tiny (about 2 inches long) and cheap (about 8 dollars) device implementing the FIDO Universal Second Factor protocol. It&amp;rsquo;s open source, too, which is awesome.
I primarily use Firefox. Unfortunately, Firefox doesn&amp;rsquo;t support U2F out of the box; you have to enable security.webauth.u2f in about:config.
Once enabled, I tried to register it with GitHub. Unfortunately, it kept on failing, despite the little green light on the U2F Zero going blue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Linux on the PC Needs a Focus on Hardware Support</title>
      <link>https://ukantjadia.me/post/why-linux-on-the-pc-needs-a-focus-on-hardware-support/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 16:28:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ukantjadia.me/post/why-linux-on-the-pc-needs-a-focus-on-hardware-support/</guid>
      <description>Linux cannot fall behind in hardware support. In fact, if we ever want to capture the desktop market, we have to race ahead.
A few days ago, I had an interesting and somewhat frustrating experience with a friend of mine. Their laptop was dying, so they asked me to give them some suggestions for a new one.
Their requirements were a computer with a display that was good for reading, enough power to be responsive and able to multitask well, and rapidly accessible storage, but not necessarily a lot of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
